# Ningna/nin-na/ Wang/won/

☑ ningna.wang@utdallas.edu | 🏠 ningnawang.github.io | 🖸 github.com/ningnawang | 🞓 Ningna Wang

# Summary\_

My research interests broadly lie in **computer graphics**, **geometry processing**, and **3D shape analysis**. My current research direction focuses on **3D medial axis** computation and its applications. I aim to explore new representations and algorithms to process geometric data more efficiently and effectively. Additionally, I am also interested in exploring **aerial path planning** for 3D urban scene reconstruction.

# **Education**

Ph.D. in Computer Science

University of Texas at Dallas | Dallas, Texas, USA

M.S. in Computer Science

Carnegie Mellon University | Pittsburgh, PA, USA

2019 - Present

2014 - 2016

B.S. in Computation Mathematics

Jilin University | Changchun, Jilin, China

2010 - 2014

## **Publications**

MATTopo: Topology-preserving Medial Axis Transform with Restricted Power Diagram **Ningna Wang**, Hui Huang, Shibo Song, Bin Wang, Wenping Wang, Xiaohu Guo

In Submission (2024). 2024

CWF: Consolidating Weak Features in High-quality Mesh Simplification [Journal Track]

Rui Xu, Longdu Liu, **Ningna Wang**, SM Chen, Shiqing Xin, Xiaohu Guo, Zichun Zhong, Taku Komura, Wenping Wang, Changhe Tu *ACM Transactions on Graphics (Proc. of SIGGRAPH)* 43.4 (2024). ACM New York, NY, USA, 2024

Globally Consistent Normal Orientation for Point Clouds by Regularizing the Winding-Number Field [Best Paper Award]
Rui Xu, Zhiyang Dou, Ningna Wang, Shiqing Xin, Shuangmin Chen, Mingyan Jiang, Xiaohu Guo, Wenping Wang, Changhe Tu

ACM Transactions on Graphics (Proc. of SIGGRAPH) (2023). ACM New York, NY, USA, 2023

S3DS: Self-supervised Learning of 3D Skeletons from Single View Images

Jianwei Hu, **Ningna Wang**, Baorong Yang, Gang Chen, Xiaohu Guo, Bin Wang to appear in ACM International Conference on Multimedia (ACM MM) (2023). 2023

Point2MM: Learning medial mesh from point clouds

Mengyuan Ge, Junfeng Yao, Zhonggui Chen, Baorong Yang, **Ningna Wang**, Xiaohu Guo *Computers & Graphics (Proceedings of CAD/Graphics)* (2023). 2023

Computing Medial Axis Transform with Feature Preservation via Restricted Power Diagram [Journal Track]

Ningna Wang, Bin Wang, Wenping Wang, Xiaohu Guo

ACM Transactions on Graphics (Proc. of SIGGRAPH Asia) 41.6 (2022) pp. 1-18. ACM New York, NY, USA, 2022

IMMAT: Mesh reconstruction from single view images by medial axis transform prediction

Jianwei Hu, Gang Chen, Baorong Yang, **Ningna Wang**, Xiaohu Guo, Bin Wang

Computer-Aided Design (CAD) 150 (2022) p. 103304. Elsevier, 2022

A method of realistic leaves modeling based on point cloud

Yinghui Wang, Wen Hao, Gang Wang, Xiaojuan Ning, Jing Tang, Zhenghao Shi, **Ningna Wang**, Minghua Zhao *Proceedings of the 12th ACM SIGGRAPH International Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and Its Applications in Industry*, 2013

# **Work Experience**

#### Department of Computer Science, University of Texas at Dallas

Dallas, Texas, USA

Research Assistant | Advisor: Dr. Xiaohu Guo

Aug 2019 - Present

- Developed a complete framework for computing the medial axis of 3D CAD meshes with **sharp-features preservation**.
- Developed a novel topology-preserving 3D medial axis computation framework based on volumetric restricted power diagram (RPD).
- Researched on new learning-based methods for mesh reconstruction via 3D skeleton prediction from single view images or point clouds.
- Developed a new method for estimating globally consistent normal orientations for a raw point cloud.
- Studied a smooth **mesh simplification** functional that simultaneously consolidates weak features in a high-quality mesh.

Teaching Assistant 2020, 2021, 2022

- Built starter code for all course projects in UTD CS6323 Computer Animation and Gaming and CS6366 Computer Graphics.
- Held office hours and graded homework for graphics-related courses.

JUNE 26, 2024

Research Intern | Advisor: Dr. Hui Huang

Oct-Dec 2023

 Conducted research on aerial path planning for drone trajectory and image capturing, efficiently yielding high-quality 3D scene reconstructions with maximum scene information and minimum flying cost.

Booking.com B.V. *Amsterdam*. *Netherlands* 

Senior Software Engineer Core Software Engineer

Nov. 2018 - July 2019 Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2018

• [System Design and Development] Responsible for the design, development, and continued operation of the hotel availability search system, which handles thousands of incoming hotel search requests per second.

- [Production Infrastructure Optimization] Significantly enhanced system stability and scalability by distributing hotel availabilities using **jump** consistent hashing, a fast consistent hash algorithm with no storage and minimal memory requirements.
- [Cross-Functional Collaboration] Collaborated seamlessly with product-side engineers and partner-side engineers to ensure the successful development and delivery of the search system.

#### The Priceline Group Inc.

#### Amsterdam, Netherlands | Seattle, WA, USA

**Graduate Software Engineer** 

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- [System Design] Developed a hotel inventory management system with a wealth of features, including property listing, yield management, and revenue analytics.
- [Feature Optimization] Implemented and experimented new features for the Genius loyalty program for various discounts and travel rewards.

## Review Service

Conference	ACM SIGGRAPH   ACM SIGGRAPH Asia	2024
Conference	International Conference on Geometric Modeling and Processing (GMP)	2024
Conference	Pacific Graphics IPC	2023
Journal	Graphical Models	2024
Journal	IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG)	2022

# Teaching

UTD Clark Summer Research Program **Teaching Assistant** 2024 Summer **Teaching Assistant CAST-STEM Bridge Summer Camp** 2024 Summer

• Supervised a team of nine high school students on a 3D talking face project.

• Lectured on basic concepts of deep learning and artificial intelligence, including CNNs, Autoencoders, VAEs, and Diffusion models.

**Teaching Assistant** UTD CS6323 Computer Animation and Gaming 2022 Fall **UTD CS6366 Computer Graphics Teaching Assistant** 2021 Spring UTD CS6334 Virtual Reality **Teaching Assistant** 2020 Spring UTD CS4347 Database Systems **Teaching Assistant** 2021 Spring, 2022 Fall **Teaching Assistant** UTD CS4332 Introduction to Programming Video Games 2019 Fall

#### Invited Talks

#### Computing Medial Axis Transform with Feature Preservation via Restricted Power Diagram

**ACM SIGGRAPH ASIA 2022** Daegu, South Korea, Dec 2022 Online, Nov 2022

Center for Digital Media Computing, Xiamen University

MATTopo: Topology-preserving Medial Axis Transform with Restricted Power Diagram Visual Computing Research Center, Shenzhen University Shenzhen, China, Nov 2023 Center for Digital Media Computing, Xiamen University Online, Jan 2024

#### Skills

**Programming** C++, Java, Python, ŁTEX, Markdown

**Technologies** OpenGL, Git, CMake, Eigen, CGAL, Geogram, libigl

**Tools** Linux/Unix, Shell (Bash/Zsh), VIM, Blender, Adobe Illustrator, Final Cut Pro

JUNE 26, 2024